Guide to the William Somerset Maugham collection, 1921-1979 (inclusive), 1921-1958 (bulk) M0013
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Clippings and notices re Maugham I (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 5. np, nd; TS 1/2p.
    “Excerpt from Maugham Collections in America, by Dr. Klaus W. Jonas, to be published Dec 56”
  - 6. London, 1954 Autumn; (6)
    “A Season of works by Somerset Maugham” 13 synopses of presented radio plays, full plays, and short stories, with an appreciation of WSM by Ivor Brown.
  - 7. Encounter, [1954]; (6)
    Waugh, Alec Maugham at Eighty
  - 8. Rutaers University, New Jersey Reprint, nd
    inscribed “For Mr. Alanson from KW Jonas”
  - 9. New York Times Book Review Hines, Jack, 1923 June 17
    “Mr. Maugham on deck and in the smoking room”. with photo of pencil drawing by Cesare.
  - 10. New York Times Book Review, 1923 May 27
    “Collected plays of England's most civilized dramatist.”
  - 11. London Illustrated News Squire, Sir John, 1952 November 15
    review of The Vagrant Mood, a collection of 6 essays. Reproduction of photograph by Karsh.
  - 12. London The Times, 1957 June 17
    Reviews of Robin Maugham's The Last Hero.
  - 13. Neve Zurcher Zeitung, 1957 April 28
    “Ze Bescuh be: Somerset Maugham” inscribed to Mr. Alanson from KW Jonas.
  - 14. San Francisco Call, 1939 January 25
    Short joke about Cakes and Ale.
  - 15. San Francisco Chronicle, 1939 January 26
    WSM visits Mrs. Frances Wilson.
  - 16. San Francisco Call, 1939 January 24
    WSM's visit to Alansons.
  - 17. Several cities., 1933 August 29; 5 articles
    Alanson's 25th anniversary as member of the San Francisco Stock Exchange.
  - 18. San Francisco Chronicle, 1949 September 18; Picture
    WSM and quote.
  - 19. Paris Le Figaro, 1924 November 22; Article
    Success of Our Betters, play by WSM.
  - 20. [San Francisco Chronicle], 1954 January 24
    This World. General note of WSM's 80th birthday and Jonas' book The Maugham Enigma.
  - 21. np Daily, nd; Picture
    WSM receiving honorary degree at Oxford.
  - 22. np Popolo d' Italia, [1925 January 15]
    “Io voglio cosi”.
  - 23. np, 1957 January 7?
    WSM's birthday invitation.
  - 24. [San Francisco Chronicle] Herb Caen column, nd
    Alanson's acquisiton of Kelly's portrait of Maugham.
  - 25. Palo Alto Times, 1957 January 24; Article
    Alanson's gift of Maugham materials to Stanford.
  - 26. Stanford News release, 1957 January 23
  - 27. [San Francisco Examiner] Herb Caen column, [1957 February 15]
    Alanson's gift.
  - 28. np, nd; 3 articles
    Alanson gift.
  - 29. San Francisco Call Bulletin, 1957 February 9
    Alanson gift to Stanford.
  - 30. San Francisco Chronicle, 1957 January 27
    Alanson gift to Stanford with picture.
  - 31. San Francisco Examiner, 1957 February 3
  - 32. Kalamazoo, Michigan Scope Weekly (Upjohn Co.), 1957 October 9
    Interview with (and two pictures of) Maugham.
  - 33. Heidelberg, Germany, Heidelberg Life, 1957 [June]
    General.
  - 34. Sports Illustrated, 1957 [June 10]
    Maugham's trip to Germany.
  - 35. Newsweek, [1957 June 12]
    “Moon and Sixpence”.
  - 36. London Times, 1958 March 24
    Viscount Maugham's (WSM's older brother? or father?) obituary.
  - 37. np Times, 1957 October 6
    WSM discusses current plays and novels.
  - 38. Nice Matin, 1955 January 23
    Alanson's visit to Cap Ferrat
  - 39. Nice Matin, 1955 September 6
    Friendship with Alanson.
  - 40. np, nd; Newsphoto
    WSM's Picasso.
  - 41. np Daily Mail, [1956 November 1]
    cartoon.
  - 42. [San Francisco Examiner], [1955 March 24]
    [Herb Caen] on WSM's 81st birthday.
  - 43., 1956 May 27; Article
    San Francisco Examiner San Francisco Street, last paragraphs about Alanson and Maugham.
  - 44. np, nd; Picture
    Lord and Lady Hope at the christening of their son.
  - 45. np Riviera Gazette, 1955 January 23; Article (with photo)
    Alanson's visit to Maugham.
  - 46. np, nd; Photo
    Maugham (and others), caption in Arabic.
  - 47. [London] Daily Telegraph, 1952 June 26; Picture
    WSM receiving honorary degree.
  - 48. Victoria, B.C., The Daily Colonist, 1951 July 26
    WSM's thoughts on growing old.
  - 49. np, [1959]; Article
    Alanson's trip to France.
  - 50. np Illustrated 6 pictures of Villa Mauresque and story of daily life with WSM at 74., 1948 October 16; (3)
  - 51. [London] Times, 1949 April 24
    “Oil shares as an investment”.
  - 52. Palo Alto Times, 1949 January 27; Picture
    San Francisco Stock Exchange party for WSM's 75th birthday.
  - 53. [London] Times, 1949 April 24
  - 54. np, [1950]
    People at WSM's 76th birthday.
  - 55. np, nd
    Maugham in London at 83.
  - 56. np Evening Standard, [1956 February 2]
    “Stolen Tune” by Robin Maugham.
  - 57. np Time, 1957 October 14
    WSM at Heidelberg.
  - 58. San Francisco Examiner, 1949 June 15
    WSM in San Francisco, interview.
  - 59. np, [1949]; Picture
    WSM and Gracie Fields.
- Alanson Memorabilia (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1. np, nd
    Well-wishes from Stock Exchange Club.
  - 2. np, nd
    Congratulatory speech on 40th anniversary of election to San Francisco Stock Exchange.
  - 3. San Francisco, 1933 August 28
    Remarks of Mr. Ross Ambler Curran on 25th anniversary of Alanson's membership in San Francisco Stock Exchange.
  - 4. np, nd
    Speech delivered in appreciation of Alanson's term on governing board [of San Francisco Stock Exchange].
  - 5. [Paris], nd February 2
    Invitation to lunch with Carl Gottfried von Seidlitz.
  - 6. Monte Carlo, nd January 25
    Invitation to birthday dinner for WSM with Carl Gottfried von Seidlitz.
  - 7. 4 menus at Restaurant de L'Hotel de Paris, Monte Carlo., 1950 January 25, 26 and February 2
  - 8. [New York], [year?] October 9
    2 tickets to American premier of WSM's Trio.
  - 9. np, nd
    Wine and Food Society's list of books in stock by Andre L. Simon.
  - 10. Written on back of sheet from desk calendar of this date are dividend figures for WSM's account., 1949 October 5
- Photographs (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1. Foochow, 1933
    Where Maugham lived.
  - 2. np PC, 1930
    “To Mabel & Bert from Uncle Hiram Lewis and Aunt Eve.”
  - 3. np, nd
    “A Sr Bertram--Jose Iglesias”.
  - 4. Alfred Hertz.
  - 5. Villa Mauresque, 1934 July 16
    A side of the house.
  - 6. [Alcatraz island from San Francisco], 2 pictures.
  - 7. To M. Alanson in kind remembrance of Princess Alexander de Beaubuay(?)., 1948 “
  - 8. Mika's picture”., 1929 “
  - 9. unidentified woman being photographed.
  - 10. Coit Tower., nd
  - 11. Photograph of oil painting of Maugham.
  - 12. negatives
    13/3/6 Added [Formerly 13/2/A]
- Photostat of “Trembling of a leaf” ms. (Box 4)
- Ms of “Trembling of a leaf” a [UNK] Section (Box 5)